Guide to the Charles Alburtus Photograph Collection Documenting Life at Yale
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Alburtus photograph collection documenting life at Yale
1948-1958
RU 775
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The materials consist of photographs and negatives taken by Charles Alburtus, primarily of Yale buildings, grounds, and individuals. Includes a few photographs of New Haven, Connecticut.
Alburtus, Charles
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and negatives taken by Charles Alburtus, primarily of Yale buildings, grounds, and individuals. Includes a few photographs of New Haven, Connecticut.
New Haven (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Photographs; Alburtus, Charles; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - Corporation: formal group portrait, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kingman Brewster, Jr., 1962, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kingman Brewster, Jr., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A. Whitney and Mary Griswold, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charles Seymour, [1964?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yale band (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graduation (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Parties, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and grounds
    - 1:2 Connecticut Hall (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1:7 Dwight Hall (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1:42 Nathan Hale Statue (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1:44 Bingham Hall (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 2:33 British Art Center, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 3:25 Pierson College Slave Quarters (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 3:25 Davenport College (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 3:43 Art and Architecture, 1962, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 4: High Street/Harkness Tower (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 4:28 Memorial Quadrangle; Harkness Tower, [1965?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 5:16 Morse College and 5:17 Ezra Stiles College, 1960-1961, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 5:16 Morse College and 5:17 Ezra Stiles College, Construction negatives, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 20-25)
    - 6:16 Payne Whitney Gymnasium, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 7:31 Sterling Memorial Library (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 8:16 Law School (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 8:16 Law School negatives, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 9:34 Calhoun College (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 9:35 Berkeley College (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 10:13 Bicentennial Buildings (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 10:18 Woodbridge Hall (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 10:24 Beinecke Library, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - 10:24 Beinecke Library, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 36-39)
    - Construction negatives
    - 12:26 Timothy Dwight College (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 13:18 Becton Engineering and Applied Science Center (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 16:1 School of Organization and Management (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 16:1 School of Organization and Management (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Construction negatives
    - 16:11 Computing Center at 60 Sachem (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - 17:9 President's House (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - 19:17 Ingall's Rink (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 19:19 Greeley Memorial Library (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - 20:6 Peabody Museum of Natural History, Interior, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - 20:14 Josiah Willard Gibbs Research Laboratory (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - 20:23 Kline Biology Tower: Roof Topping Party, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - 20:23 Kline Biology Tower (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - 20:25 Pierson Sage Parking Garage (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - 22: Medical Center (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Public Information Office, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Accelerator, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Aerials, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Objects and memorabilia: Yale Symbols (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
  - Objects and memorabilia: [Silver?] (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Individuals
    - Bowles, Chester (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Carr, Rev. Aute L (at the Divinity School): negatives., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Cozza, Carmen, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Ripley, S. Dillon: Peabody Museum party, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Hindemith, Paul, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - King Hussein, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - May, Georges, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Morley, Christopher (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Schollander, Donald, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Segal, Erich (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Unidentified, 1961, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - New Haven (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - New Haven: Insurance Building, Whitney Ave. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Faculty and staff events: Southeast Asia Studies, Bedoyo dancers (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Miscellaneous: buildings (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Miscellaneous: Hartford buildings (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Oversize Photographs: Buildings and grounds
    - 3:25 Pierson College Slave Quarters (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - 4:28 Harkness Tower (Memorial Quadrangle) (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - 4:28 Memorial Quadrangle, [1965?] (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - 5:17 Ezra Stiles College (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - 6:16 Payne Whitney Gymnasium (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - 7:31 Sterling Memorial Library (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - 8:16 Law School (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - 10:24 Beinecke Library (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - 19:17 Ingalls Rink (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - 20:6 Peabody Museum (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - 20:23 Kline Biology Tower (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - 22:167 School of Public Health and Epidemiology (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Unidentified building (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Unidentified: steam tunnel (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Unidentified: construction (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - New Haven Green, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Oversize Photographs: Individuals
    - Acheson, Dean Gooderham
      General
      See: box 5, folder 103
    - Alburtus, Charles (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Brewster, Kingman, Jr. (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Canfield, Curtis F., MacLeish, Archibald: Production of AJ.B.@, [1958?] (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Female dining hall employee (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Goetze, Albrecht and Stephens, Ferris J., [1962?] (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Hindemith, Paul, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Laroree, Leonard Woods (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - MacLeish, Archibald
      General note
      See: box 4, folder 95
    - Seymour, Charles (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Stephens, Ferris J.
      See: box 4, folder 97
    - Sterling Courtyard ceremony (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Truman, Harry S. and Acheson, Dean Gooderham (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Walpole, Horace (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Weaver, Howard (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Yale, Elihu: Corporation Room painting (Folder 6)
    - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Esquire article, 1967: Roberts, Steven V., "Is It Too Late for a Man of Honesty, High Purpose and Intelligence to Be Elected President of the United States in 1968?", 1967 October (Box 7, Folder 107)